[{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 1",
    "question": "The back is located and delimited by:",
    "answers": ["b"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Anterior surface of the trunk, below the skull and above the coccyx",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Posterior face of the trunk, below the neck and above the buttocks",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Anterior surface of the trunk, below the neck and above the coccyx",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Posterior face of the trunk, below the skull and above the buttocks",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 2",
    "question": "Which of the following structures is not located on the back?",
    "answers": ["d"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Spine",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Ribs",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Scapulas",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Clavicles",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 3",
    "question": "The spine forms:",
    "answers": ["d"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Axial skeleton and appendicular skeleton",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Appendicular skeleton and back skeleton",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Appendicular skeleton, neck skeleton and skull skeleton",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Skeleton of the neck and back, and the main part of the axial skeleton",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 4",
    "question": "How many vertebrae does the human body consist of?",
    "answers": ["a"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "33 vertebrae, 24 of which are pre-sacral",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "32 vertebrae, 23 of which are pre-sacral",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "31 vertebrae, 22 of which are pre-sacral",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "30 vertebrae, 21 of which are pre-sacral",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 5",
    "question": "A typical vertebra consists of:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "02 vertebral bodies, 01 vertebral arch and 07 processes",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "01 vertebral body, 02 vertebral arches and 06 processes",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "01 vertebral body, 01 vertebral arch and 07 processes",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "02 vertebral bodies, 01 vertebral arch and 05 processes",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 6",
    "question": "Seven processes originate from the vertebral arch of a typical vertebra, namely:",
    "answers": ["b"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "02 spinous processes, 02 transverse processes and 03 articular processes",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "01 spinous process, 02 transverse processes and 04 articular processes",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "02 spinous processes, 01 transversal process and 04 articular processes",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "01 spinous process, 01 transversal process and 05 articular processes",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 7",
    "question": "The spine consists of 24 pre-sacral vertebrae, which are:",
    "answers": ["d"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "06 cervical, 11 thoracic and 07 lumbar",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "07 cervical, 10 thoracic and 07 lumbar",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "06 cervical, 12 thoracic, and 06 lumbar",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "07 cervical, 12 thoracic and 05 lumbar",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 8",
    "question": "What is the main characteristic of cervical vertebrae?",
    "answers": ["a"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Presence of the foramen in the transversal process",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of the foramen in the spinous process",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of the foramen in the joint process",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of the foramen in the body",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 9",
    "question": "The first and second cervical vertebrae are named, respectively:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Axios and Axis",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Atlas and Atlos",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Atlas and Axis",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Atlas and Axios",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 10",
    "question": "The main characteristic of thoracic vertebrae is:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Presence of intercostal foveae",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of foramen in the transversal process",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of coastal foveas",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of foramen in the spinous process",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 11",
    "question": "The main characteristics of the lumbar vertebrae are:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Presence of cylindrical bodies, thin blades and presence of costal foveas",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of massive bodies, robust blads and presence of costal foveas",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of massive bodies, robust blads and absence of costal foveas",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Presence of cylindrical bodies, thin blades and absence of costal foveas",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 12",
    "question": "The sacrum is characterized by being:",
    "answers": ["a"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "A large, cuneiform bone, triangular in shape and normally composed in adults by 05 fused sacral vertebrae",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "A large, cuneiform bone, rectangular in shape and normally composed of 06 fused sacral vertebrae in adults",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "A small, cuneiform bone, rectangular in shape and normally composed in adults by 06 fused sacral vertebrae",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "A small, cuneiform bone, triangular in shape, and normally composed in adults by 05 fused sacral vertebrae",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 13",
    "question": "The coccyx is characterized by:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "A large, triangular bone, normally formed by 04 cuneiform vertebrae",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "A large, rectangular bone, normally formed by 04 rudimentary vertebrae",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "A small, triangular bone, normally formed by 04 rudimentary vertebrae",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "A small, rectangular bone, normally formed by 04 cuneiform vertebrae",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 14",
    "question": "Which of the following joints do not correspond to spinal joints?",
    "answers": ["d"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Atlantoaxial joints",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Sacroiliac joints",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Costovertebral joints",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Sternocleidomastoid joint",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 15",
    "question": "The back muscles are classified in 03 groups, which are:",
    "answers": ["b"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Extrinsic group, intrinsic group and deep group",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Superficial group, intermediate group and deep group",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Superficial group, deep group and intrinsic group",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Extrinsic group, intrinsic group and surface group",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 16",
    "question": "Of the following muscles, which does not correspond to the dorsal region muscle:",
    "answers": ["a"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "M. Zygomatic",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "M. gluteus maximus",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "M. trapezius",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "M. Rhomboid",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 17",
    "question": "The spinal cord is enlarged in 02 regions for innervation of the members, which are:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Cranial intumescence and caudal intumescence",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Upper swelling and lower swelling",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Cervical intumescence and caudal intumescence",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Cervical intumescence and lumbosacral intumescence",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 18",
    "question": "Which of the following does not correspond to the nerve responsible for dorsal innervation?",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Major Occipital Nerve",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Suboccipital nerve",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Hypoglossal nerve",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Posterior branches of C3-C0",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 19",
    "question": "What are the spinal meninges?",
    "answers": ["a"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Duramater, arachnoid and piamater",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Intramater, Inframater and submater",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Duramater, fragilmater and piamater",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Intramater, Inframater and supermater",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
},{
    "category": "dorso",
    "title": "Question 20",
    "question": "Spinal cord vascularization occurs through the arteries:",
    "answers": ["c"],
    "options": [{
            "label": "Upper spinal artery and lower spinal artery",
            "value": "a"
        },{
            "label": "Upper spinal artery and even posterior spinal arteries",
            "value": "b"
        },{
            "label": "Anterior spinal artery and even posterior spinal arteries",
            "value": "c"
        },{
            "label": "Anterior spinal artery, and even inferior spinal arteries",
            "value": "d"
        }
    ]
}]